本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：Marvin    Silmar      校对：joanna     时间轴：虫不知
特效：Will      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
这个计划很大胆啊  怀特先生
It's a bold plan, Mr. White.
你确定要这么做吗
You sure this is the way to go?
谢了
Gracias.
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第三集
他还记得什么
What does he remember?
没多少  他来的时候就虚脱且神志不清了
Not a whole lot. He came in dehydrated and disoriented.
给他输液后  他恢复得挺快
But once we gave him fluids he stabilized pretty quickly.
但是  我是说  他知道自己在哪儿吗
But, I mean... he knows where he is?
是的  当然了
Yes, absolutely.
就是前几天的事想不起来了
It's only the last day or so that seem to be missing.
进去吧  他应该醒了
Go on in, he's probably awake.
天啊
My God.
真是对不起
I'm so sorry.
过来这儿
Come here.
你知道我是谁  对吗
You know who I am, right?
是的儿子  我认得你  来  抱抱你老爹
Yes, son. I know who you are. Come here, give your old man a hug.
见到你们太高兴了
It's so good to see you.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
好些了
Better.
我觉得神志清醒了
I feel like myself.
真的  我是指
Really, I mean, in...
前几天的都记不起来了  但是
The last couple days are missing, but...
除此之外  感觉还挺好
Other than that, I feel fine.
天啊  沃尔特
My God, Walt.
你这都怎么过的呀
What a day this has been?
汉克叔叔  他跟人发生了枪战
So, Uncle Hank, he was in a shoot-out.
枪战
A shoot-out?
他杀了个什么人  大毒枭之类的
He killed some guy. Some big drug dealer.
-汉克叔叔把他干掉了  -天  他没事吧
- Uncle Hank wasted him. - My God. Is he all right?
-当然没事了  -在哪发生的
- Absolutely fine. - But where did this happen?
-他怎么会...  -沃尔特  一切都好
- How could he be... - Walt, everything's okay.
我们都没事
We're all okay.
还不清楚是什么引发的吗
And no idea what caused it?
不过他们打算做一整套检查  所以
But they're gonna run a whole series of tests, so...
但到底会怎样呢
But what could it be?
他们有没有说最坏的情况会怎样
Did they give you a worst-case scenario?
我真的觉得  没必要提前想这么多
I really...there's no point in getting ahead of ourselves, so...
在哪个超市
Which supermarket?
是那种大型超市  还是连锁店
Is it, like, a big one?  Like, a chain?
玛丽
Marie.
别误会
Don't get me wrong.
我觉得这是好事
I think it's just great that
他总算回来了  病情也有所好转
he's back and he's feeling better.
我只是  我是说
I just, I mean...
他  一丝不挂
He... naked?
他真的
He was...
一丝不挂
naked...
一丝不挂啊
naked.
还是在超市里
In a supermarket.
不会是全食超市吧[高档杂货零售商]
It wasn't Whole Foods, was it?
不管怎么样  我都要尽快赶去你那边
In any case, I'm gonna get over there as soon as I can.
玛丽  现在先别担心这个
Don't worry about it right now, Marie.
汉克怎么样
How's Hank?
我赶过来才见到他不过三十秒
I ran over here and I get to see him all
他就被带走了
Of 30 seconds before they yanked him away.
就只希望...就今天一天
You'd think... today of all days,
他们会让他准时下班回家
They'd let him go home on time.
但是他怎么样
But how is he?
到底怎么样
Really?
他可是坚不可摧的  你知道的
He's indestructible, you know that.
我亮明身份  然后告诉嫌犯
I identified myself and told the suspect
举起手来  转身面对我
to show his hands, turn and face me.
这时我认出嫌犯是塞拉曼加先生
At this point, I identified the suspect as Mr. Salamanca
并且发现他腹部有一处枪伤
and observed what appeared to be a gunshot wound in his midsection.
他在你到达之前就中枪了吗
He was shot previous to your arrival?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我再一次要求他举起手来
Again I instructed him to show his hands.
塞拉曼加先生朝车子冲了过去
Mr. Salamanca lunged toward the vehicle
接着就向我开火  我确认武器是M16突击步枪
And fired on me with what I ascertained to be an M16 assault rifle.
我还击并寻找掩护  塞拉曼加先生不断向我扫射
I returned fire and sought cover as Mr. Salamanca proceed to engage me.
当他停下装填弹药时
When he paused to reload...
我趁机将他一击毙命
I was able to take an effective shot.
施拉德探员
Agent Schrader.
你为何会在没有增援的情况下
What were you doing in a shooting fight
一个人参与枪战呢
On your own, with no backup?
塞拉曼加先生的出现很出乎我的意料
Mr.Salamanca's presence was not something I'd anticipated.
-我此行原是处理别的事  -什么别的事
- I was tending to another matter. - What other matter?
是桩不相干的家务事
An unrelated family matter.
据我所知  是为了找你姐夫
Searching for your brother-in-law as I understand.
-你姐夫  -是的  长官
- Your brother-in-law?  - Yes, sir.
他后来已被找到了  他没事
He's since been found. He's fine.
整件事完全是一场误会
The whole thing was a misunderstanding.
但当时他失踪好几个小时了
But at the time, he'd been missing for several hours and,
因为他病得很重  全家都很焦急
since he's in poor health, the whole family was concerned.
我去找了他的朋友和熟人谈话
I was talking to his friends and acquaintances
想查清楚他的下落
Trying to get a fix on his whereabouts.
现场的蒙特卡洛车是他之前一个学生的
The Monte Carlo at the scene belonged to a former student of his, a...
他叫杰西·平克曼
Jesse Pinkman.
我在追踪平克曼先生的车
I was tracking down Mr. Pinkman's car
正好遇上了塞拉曼加先生
When I came across Mr. Salamanca.
这个平克曼又是怎么回事
And what about this Pinkman?
他的车为什么在犯罪现场  查过他的底了吗
What was his car doing at the crime scene?Have you run him down yet?
还没  但我们正在着手调查
Not yet, but we're working on it.
伙计  他们就像耶和华见证人[一种宗教信仰]  不会放弃的
Man, they're like Jehovah's witnesses.They don't give up.
我搞不懂  他们为什么不直接把门踹开
I don't get it. Why don't they just kick your door down?
-他们需要正当理由  -"正当理由"
- They need probable cause.  - "Probable cause?"
喂  你做什么了  抢银行了吗
Yo, what'd you do?  Rob a bank?
我告诉过你  这事很他妈严重
I told you, this is serious shit.
-我就像个逃犯一样  -好吧
- I'm like an outlaw. - Ok
开工吧
Let's do this.
我的老天
Holy christ!
你简直是威利·旺卡[《查理与巧克力工厂》中主角]
You're Willy Wonka!
你就是威利·旺卡  而我拿到了金券
You are Willy Wonka, and I got the golden ticket!
快让我登上你的魔法船  伙计
Put me on your magical boat, man!
让我在冰毒的河流里畅游吧
Sail me down your chocolatey river of meth!
[此段对话模仿电影《查理与巧克力工厂》]
你把伪麻黄素放哪儿了
So, where you keep the pseudo?
我们用苯丙酮法制毒  看见那个桶了吗
It's a P2P cook. That barrel?
那是甲胺水溶液  有那个就不用伪麻黄素了
Aqueous Methylamine. With that, you don't need pseudo.
拜托  来帮下我  伙计
Come on, help me out, man!
不用伪麻黄素
No pseudo?
过来我这  小可爱
Come to me, beautiful baby.
我会好生待你的
I'm gonna be so good to you.
拿着这个  给你
Just take this, here.
我不能就这么让你毁了这地方
But I can't just let you break this down.
那可是亵渎
That'd be sacrilege!
我告诉过你  这就是为什么我们来这
I told you, that's why we're here.
-你看见那些条子了吧  -当然
- You saw the cops! All right?  - Sure.
我们不能赶制一批货么
But couldn't we just cook one quick batch?
-路上用的  -不行  别想了行不
- For the road?  - No, forget it, all right?
得处理掉这些东西  就是现在
This stuff has to go, like, now.
这是你欠我的
You owe me!
我们目前交情是还行
We're cool and all, but
但我不会忘记你曾那么对我的
I ain't forgetting you just left me stranded.
天  猴子
God, Badger!
别给我添乱
Don't mess with me!
懂了没
Got it?
懂了
Yeah, I got it.
我的天
My God.
行了  就这些
Okay, that's all of it.
这是个糟糕的选择
This is a bad choice.
你确定这家伙没问题吗
You sure about this guy?
他可是相当  相当棒
He's totally, totally cool.
他是我表兄
He's my cousin.
-喂  我们说好了吧  500块  -那可不行  得1000块
- Yo, what'd we say, 500?  - We didn't say, and it's 1,000.
1000块
$1,000?
拜托  你往哪拖啊  西雅图吗
C'mon, where you towing it, man, Seattle?
跟距离没关系  是货的问题
It ain't the miles, it's the cargo.
伙计  我身上总共只有
Dude, all I got on me is...
560块
$560.
这样的话
You know what?
克洛维斯  他晚点会付清余额的
Clovis! He'll pay you the rest later.
他不会食言的  杰西是个正直的人
He's totally good for it! Jesse's a stand-up dude.
是吗  你是"正直的人"吗
That right? You a "stand-up dude"?
是啊  我是
Yeah, I am.
我会付你另外500块的
I will get you the other $500.
还要给500块
$500 more.
说话算话吧
Your word's bond, right?
对
Right.
我可救了场啊  我可替你担保了
I saved your skinny ass, yo. I totally vouched for you.
你现在到底在做什么
What are you doing now, exactly?
我会给你争取大概两个小时
I'm giving you, like, two hours
然后我会用公用电话告发你  而不是手机
and then I'm calling on a pay phone, not a cell phone.
你可不能用自己的真名
You're not using your own name.
当然  我会按你说的做  但是
I mean,obviously.Look,dude,I'll do,like, what you said,but
为什么  你这么做到底想干什么
Why? Why do you gotta go and do this?
他们需要正当理由
They need probable cause.
我就给他们一个
I'm giving it to them.
你记得的最后一件事是什么
What's the last thing you remember?
我正开车回家  我想是的
I was driving home...I think.
你还记得怎么进的家门吗
Do you remember coming home?
你进门来  我问你为什么上气不接下气
You came in, and I asked why you were out of breath?
你不记得我在泡澡时  你跟我说过话吗
You don't remember talking to me when I was in the bathtub?
抱歉  我不记得了
No, I'm sorry, I don't.
没别的了吗  没有一闪而过的画面吗
Nothing else? No fleeting images?
不知道
I don't know.
我当时正沿着马路或高速路走
I was walking down some road or highway...
很多车灯照过来
With a lot of headlights,
我记得我很害怕
And I remember feeling fear.
谢谢
Thank you.
当然  这里有些有好消息
There's definitely some good news here.
核磁共振扫描没发现转移瘤
The MRI shows no metastases.
就是说癌细胞没有扩散到大脑吗
Meaning the cancer hasn't spread to the brain?
是的  情况还不错
Yeah, we're looking really good.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
那到底是怎么回事呢
So, what was it, then?
没有中风或者癫痫发作的迹象
Well, there's no sign of stroke or seizure.
考虑到你的状况  血液检查也没什么问题
And considering your condition, the blood panel looks good.
那这到底是什么情况
Then what are we talking about?
怎么回事
What happened?
就目前来看  我们实在...下不了定论
As of right now, we really...can't say.
抱歉  虽然我不太了解这方面
Forgive me. Granted, this is not my field,
但是这会不会跟我服用的
But isn't it possible that this had something to do
那些治疗的药物有关呢
with all the prescriptions I've been taking?
有止吐药
There's the antiemetic,
有止咳药
the antitussive,
又是这又是那
the this, the that,
更别说化疗本身了
not to mention the Chemo itself.
过去几天中断治疗  没吃这些药
And being off all of them for the past few days,
我必须承认  我感觉
I have to say, I'm feeling...
好多了
much better.
还有  我们去拿药的时候
And when we pick up these medications,
说明书就像胳膊一样长
the information sheets are as long as your arm.
我是说  一页页都写的副作用和警告什么的
I mean, it's page after page of side effects and... and warnings.
对  的确  会不会就是这么简单
Right, exactly. Could it be that simple?
当然  我们会多加注意的
We'll take another look at that, sure.
沃尔特  我理解你最近一直比较压抑
Walt, I understand that you've been kind of stressed out lately.
-压抑吗  我不觉得我  -沃尔特  拜托
- Stressed out?  No, I don't think I'm...  - Walt, please.
说"压抑"已经算客气的了
"Stressed out" is putting it...mildly.
我最近可能是有点多虑了
I guess I've had a lot on my mind lately,
但我说了  我感觉好多了
but as I've said, I'm feeling much better.
我们是不是该讨论下我何时能出院
Shouldn't we be talking about when I can get out of here?
现在还为时尚早
That may still be a ways down the road.
"为时尚早"
"A ways down the road?"
我觉得下一步应该安排一个精神评估
Actually, I think our next move is to schedule a psychiatric evaluation.
真有这个必要吗
Now, is that absolutely necessary?
没人喜欢老呆在医院里  我理解
Nobody likes being in the hospital. I get that.
但是我们必须搞清楚这次意外的起因
But until we know what caused this incident
我们不确定它还会不会复发
we can't be certain it won't recur.
[汽车旅馆  欢迎光临  内设全频道有线电视
24小时营业  宾至如归  服务友好]
最后一口吗
That your last hit?
动作快点
Finish it quick.
趴下
Get on your stomach now!
翻身  动作快点
Get over, roll. Do it now!
我在走  我在走
I'm going, I'm going.
怎么了  我做了什么
What's going on? What'd I do?
我猜你就是杰西·平克曼
Jesse Pinkman, I presume.
-怎么  老兄  -再说一遍
- What, man?  - Tell me again.
再一遍吗
Again?
有什么说的  我跟她就是开派对  仅此而已
What's there to tell, okay?Her and I were partying,that's it.
从周六晚上开始是吧  连开三天啊
Since Saturday night? Partying for three days straight.
就只玩女人  吸从你兄弟屠库那里搞到的冰毒
Just bumping uglies and smoking that crystal you got from your pal Tuco?
塔库  我不认识什么塔库
Taco?  I don't know any Taco.
我他妈肯定我没吸过什么冰毒
And I damn sure didn't say anything about no crystal.
-三天  你肯定会饿的吧  -对啊
- Three days, you must have got hungry.  - Yeah, I guess.
你们叫过外卖吗
You order take-out?
-叫过  -从哪叫的
- Yeah. - Where from?
你们是从角落墙缝里
You get yourself a little of that Moo goo gai pan
叫了一点那什么蘑菇鸡片对吧
from that chink place around the corner?
不  没有  我们从自动售货机里买东西
No, no, we didn't. We got stuff from the vending machine.
芳韵  还有热口袋[均为速食品牌]
You know, Funyuns. I had a Hot Pocket.
芳韵和热口袋
Funyuns and Hot Pockets?
你没注意到你的车丢了吗
And you didn't notice your car was gone?
没  直到你们撞开门进屋
No, not until you guys went and busted down the door.
谁来赔那门的钱啊
Now who's gonna pay for that?
管理员肯定要不会放过我的
Management's gonna be on my ass for sure.
-为什么你不接手机  -手机在我车里
- Why didn't you answer your cell phone?  - It was in my car.
-真的吗  -是的
- That right?  - Yeah.
我们找到了你的车
We found your car,
但是你的手机不在里面
but your phone wasn't in it.
你们找到了我的车
You found my car?
找到了我的车吗
太棒了  缉毒署真牛  太好了
Awesome!  DEA all the way!  Yes！
既然提到财产损失  你有没有
Since we're talking about missing property, did you...
在车里落下什么东西
Leave anything else in the car?
比如什么
Like what?
比如什么  比如
Like what, like,
比如这个
Like this?
67900块
67,900 and, uh...
外加20块
20 dollars.
那不是我的
That's not mine.
不是你的吗
That's not yours?
他说不是他的  格米
Says it's not his, Gomie.
天  我还以为是你的呢
Gee, I really thought this might be yours.
是我的就好了
I wish.
无人认领的毒品赃款  不错啊
Unclaimed drug money. Nice.
你知道我们搞到什么了吧  格米
You know what we got here, Gomie, don't ya?
能买辆新的缉毒用车
That's a new interdiction van right there.
肯定还能买些垒球球衣  我们正好要用到
Definitely some new softball jerseys, 'cause we need 'em.
还好屠库已经死翘翘了
Good thing Tuco's already dead.
要是我丢了这么一笔钱  我会去自杀
I lost this kind of money, I'd wanna kill myself.
你头头是谁  小杂种
So, who's your chief, li'l injun?
什么
What?
-什么意思  -你讲的全是屁话
- What does that even mean? - I think your story's bullshit.
我认为你认识屠库·塞拉曼加
I think you know who Tuco Salamanca was.
我认为你的车停在那说明你也在那儿
I think your car was there 'cause you were there.
我赶到的时候屠库中了弹
Tuco had a bullet in him when I got there,
我认为这跟你脱不了干系
And I think you know something about that, too.
你这话什么意思
So, what are you saying?
说我杀人了吗
I shot someone?
用什么  枪吗
With, like, a gun?
你
You?
你只有本事往面巾纸里打手枪吧[隐晦意]
Now, Only shooting you do is into a kleenex.
但我想你知道是谁干的
But I think you know the badass who did.
听着  我一直在跟温蒂开派对
Look, I was partying with Wendy.
芳韵和嘿咻
Funyuns and boom-boom.
不
No.
我可不这么想
I don't think so.
跟你这么说吧  我们打算
Tell you what, we're gonna,
跟你那位瘦小火辣的女友谈谈
go talk to that skinny, yeast factory of a girlfriend you got.
你知道吗
And you know what?
我有种感觉  她会把你卖了
I got a feeling she's gonna, you know, roll on you.
你给我老实呆着
Don't go nowhere.
我的根汁汽水呢  快点儿啊
Where's my root beer? Come on!
我要撒尿  我血糖低
I gotta pee, and I got low blood sugar.
-我生病了  -生病
- I got medical issues. - Medical issues?
什么病  是你男人满足不了你
Like what kind of medical issues? You got penis withdrawal?
还是办事的时候被人打断了
You got "Schlongus interruptus"?
听着  温蒂  你老实交代
Wendy, listen, talk to me,
我就给你根汁汽水  让你去厕所
And you get a root beer and a tinkle.
-说说这三天的事  -我说过了
- Now tell me the last three days. - I told you,
我们从周六就一直混在一起
We were shacked up since Saturday.
你俩都没离开过房间  一分钟也没有
Neither of you left the room? Not even for a little, little minute?
一秒钟也没有吗
Not even for a second?
一秒钟  我不确定  可能吧
For a second? I dunno, maybe.
可能
Maybe?
杰西有没有离开过房间
Did Jesse leave the room?
他有  是不是
He did, didn't he?
温蒂  说吧  说吧  温蒂
Wendy, you can do it. You can do it, Wendy.
我知道你想回去透透风  温蒂
You know you wanna go back to giving windys, Wendy.
是你  我认识你
It's you. I know you.
你就是黑色卡车里那个人
You're the one in the black truck.
你让我跟那孩子上床
You wanted me to do that kid.
-什么  -那个拄拐杖的孩子
- What? - The kid with the crutches.
-穿球衣的孩子  -别岔开话题
- The football player. - How about we stay on topic?
听好了  杰西星期六晚上11点过来的
Look, Jesse came over to the palace at eleven o'clock Saturday night.
我们一直在一起  他一直没离开房间
We were together the whole time, and he never left the room.
我要说的就这些
And that's all I'm saying about that.
行了  我的根汁汽水呢
Now, come on. Where's my root beer?
你让她跟那个穿球衣的孩子上床  你个变态
You wanted her to bang a football player, you big ball pervert?
这事说来话长  格米
It's a long story, Gomie.
那是当然的  我要你讲给我听
I'm sure it is, and I wanna hear it,
但我们得先放了平克曼
But first we gotta kick Pinkman loose.
还不行  我要最后审一下那小混蛋
Not yet. I got one more shot at that little skid mark.
你睡眠怎么样
And how are you sleeping?
很好  大部分晚上都是
Fine. Most nights.
不错
Good.
你脑子里是否有经常重现的想法或图像
Have you noticed any recurring thoughts or images,
让你挥之不去的念头呢
Things you can't get out of your head?
有没有内疚或者受迫的感觉
How about feelings of guilt or persecution?
没有  医生  听我说
No, look, Doctor.
我不想冒犯
I don't mean to be rude,
可我们这是在干嘛
But where is this going, exactly?
我们在开始治疗  沃特  正在进行治疗
We're starting a process, Walt, an ongoing process.
你喜欢我叫你沃特还是沃尔特
Do you prefer Walt or Walter?
需要进行多久
Ongoing for how long?
我们才刚刚见面  这很难说
I just met you, it's hard to say.
有可能是几天  几周  或几个月
We could be talking about days, weeks, months.
听我说  医生  我真的没事了
Look, Doctor, I feel fine, really.
而且  如果真的有必要治疗
Now, if this is truly necessary,
我不能出院接受治疗吗
Can't I continue as an outpatient?
神游状态是非常严重的事件
A fugue state is a very serious event.
如果你驾车的时候发病怎么办
What if you were to disassociate while driving?
如果你使自己陷入险境被警察枪击怎么办
What if you were to get into a situation where you could be shot by the police?
你明白  我们不能让你出院
You understand, we can't allow you to leave until we're certain
除非确定你的症状非复发性的
What happenedwas a non-recurring event.
单凭你说自己没事是不解决问题的
Saying you feel fine doesn't solve this.
能跟我讲讲医患保密协议吗
Would you tell me about patient confidentiality?
你很直接
It's very straightforward.
未经你同意
Without your permission,
我不得向任何人透露你我谈话内容
I can't disclose anything you tell me to anyone.
我的亲属呢
What about my family?
亲属  警方  任何人都不可以
Not your family, not to the police. Not to anyone.
除非你威胁要杀死某人
The only exception would be if you threatened to kill someone.
那样我可以告诉被威胁者  也仅限被威胁者
Then I'd be able to tell that person, but only that person.
而你作为一名执业医生
And you, as a medical practioner,
完全受此条款约束
You abide by these strictures absolutely.
好吧
All right.
我根本没失忆
There was no fugue state.
我什么都记得
I remember everything.
真相是
The truth is,
我无法忍受在那间房子里多待一秒
I couldn't stand to spend another second in that house.
我只是想离开
I just had to get out.
所以我就离开了
And so I left.
我想都没想  只是做了
I didn't think about it. I just did it.
我走了很长时间
I walked for a long time,
走到走不动的时候  就搭便车
And when I couldn't walk anymore, I hitchhiked.
我去了盖洛普市
I got as far as Gallup, and...
然后觉得该回家了
Then it was just time to come home.
这么说
So,
全裸着在超市里被人发现
Being found naked in a supermarket,
只是你让谎言顺利通过的办法
That was your way of giving credibility to a lie?
这样他们就不会问你为何失踪了
Of avoiding questions about your disappearance?
为什么离家出走
Why run away?
你想要逃离什么
What did you feel you had to run from?
医生  我妻子怀孕7个月了
Doctor, my wife is seven months pregnant
而我们原本没打算再要孩子的
With a baby we didn't intend.
我15岁的儿子患有脑瘫
My 15-year-old son has cerebral palsy.
我只是个资历很高的高中化学教员
I am an extremely overqualified high school chemistry teacher.
能上班的时候  年薪也就4万3千7百块
When I can work, I make $43,700 per year.
我眼睁睁地看着自己的同事和朋友
I have watched all of my colleagues and friends
一个个都混得比我好  而再过18个月
Surpass me in every way imaginable, and within 18 months,
我就要死了
I will be dead.
你还问我为什么出走
And you ask why I ran?
格米  劳驾来问问他
Gomie, you wanna do the honors?
-什么意思  -意思是"是"
- What's that mean? - That means "yes."
按铃是"是"  不按铃是"否"
"Yes" is a bell, "no" is no bell.
得了吧  这真是扯淡
Come on, this is bullshit!
你看看他
Look at this dude.
他连自己在哪个星球上都不知道
He doesn't even know what planet he's living on.
迪奥
Tio,
我们是在火星上吗
Are we on the planet Mars?
我们是在土星上吗
Are we on the planet Saturn?
我们是在地球上吗
Are we on the planet Earth?
迪奥  今天是星期五吗
Tio, is today Friday?
今天是星期一吗
Is today Monday?
今天是星期二吗
Is today Tuesday?
看来他清楚得很呢  开始吧
Seems like he's all there. Let's go for it.
这个人昨天去过你家吗
Was this man at your house yesterday?
这边这个人  他去过你家  是不是
This guy right here, he was at your house, right?
他是不是跟你外甥屠库有交易
Was he doing business with your nephew Tuco?
你害怕这个人吗
Are you scared of this man?
不  他不害怕
Nah, he's not scared.
说呀  老爷子
Come on, granddad.
你不想帮忙吗
Don't you want to help us out?
老天
Oh, man.
看来他是不想
I guess that's a no.
我早跟你说了  他是个老黑帮
I told you, numbnuts. This guy's OG.
在圣昆丁关了17年都没开过口
Kept his mouth shut for 17 years in San Quentin.
不管得没得中风
Stroke or no stroke,
老派墨西哥黑帮就不跟警察合作
Old school gangbang Mexicans don't help the Feds.
已经完事了  至少值得一试
All right already. It was worth a try at least.
我们得放了平克曼
We gotta kick Pinkman loose.
没事的  他也不是什么大人物
It's all right. He's nobody anyway.
你是说你相信他编的那个残疾故事
What, you telling me you buy that lame-ass story of his?
我宁愿相信那个残疾故事
I buy that lame-ass story more than I buy he had anything to do
也不信他能跟枪杀屠库扯上关系
With shooting Tuco, man.
爸  你好 老爸
Dad? Hey, Dad.
能听见吗
Can you hear me?
我很好  我
I'm fine. I'm, uh...
什么  她打电话了
What's... She did?
我没收到留言
No, I didn't get any messages.
是这么回事  我电话丢了
You know, actually I lost my phone,
太忙了没时间买新的
And I've been too busy to get a new one.
我忙得跟什么似的  都是正事
I've been busy as sh... Totally productive.
知道吗  我马上就有工作了
Hey, you know what? I'm actually zeroing in on a job.
数据输入  我们谈起过的
Data entry, like we talked about.
我非常高兴
I'm totally amped.
你能来接我一下吗
Could you give me a ride?
我现在在城里  我的车...
I'm actually, I'm downtown and my car's in the...
没事  没关系的
No, that's cool.
等你有时间我再打电话
I will call you later when you have some...
我懂  我懂
I get it. I get it.
谢谢
Thanks.
你现在去哪儿
So, what are you doing now?
华夫松饼店
Waffle House?
华夫松饼店不错
Waffle House is good.
是公用电话
Pay phone?
是公用电话  地方隐蔽没人跟踪
Pay phone, in the middle of nowhere, nobody followed.
你怎么样
How'd it go?
很好  你呢
Okay. You?
他们把我整得够呛
They sweated me plenty but
最后还是把我放了
They finally cut me loose.
-这么说你要出院了  -明天
- So you getting out of there? - Tomorrow.
谁抓的你
So, who came for you?
禁毒署吗  他们问你什么了
The DEA? What did they ask you?
问题就在这  知道吗  你那个浑球连襟
That's the thing, you know. Your scumbag brother-in-law
拿走了我的应急基金
Took my rainy day fund.
你的什么  什么意思
Your what? What is that?
我的应急基金  6万8千块  懂啦
My rainy day fund, $68,000, okay?
狗娘养的混蛋  还当我面笑那么开心
Cueball son of a bitch laughed in my face.
现在我账户里只剩80块了
Now I got like $80 to my name.
等等  他都知道什么  他知道那是你的钱吗
Wait, wait. What does he know? Does he know it's your money?
他  他知道个屁
No, man, he doesn't know shit, okay?
计划成功了
The plan worked.
他们信了
They bought it.
可我还有账单要付呢  伙计  我完蛋了
I've got bills due, man. I'm screwed.
他提到我了吗
Did he mention my name?
没有  多谢关心
No, thanks for caring.
-地下室怎么样了  -收拾好了
- What about the basement? - It's clean.
制毒车呢
And the RV?
猴子的表兄把它拖到自家车库了  不用担心
Badger's cousin took it to his garage. It's safe.
他能把车修好吗
Can he get it running again?
修它干嘛
Why?
我们继续制毒
So we can cook.
你还想继续制毒
So you still wanna cook?
说真的
Seriously?
有什么不同  杰西
What's changed, Jesse?
73万7千
737,000...
21磅
21 pounds...
减去手头的现金
Minus cash on hand...
手头的现金
Cash on hand.
对不起  亲爱的  我吵醒你了吗
Sorry, honey. Did I wake you?
没有  我没睡
No, I was awake.
要玉米片吗
Want some cornflakes?
要
Sure.
你还好吧
You okay?
西南面那家苯胺厂  又在看
Southwest Aniline? Again?
这是什么
What's this?
这是我们在你老乡那儿发现的蓝色冰毒
It's the blue meth we found up by your late homie.
屠库要是我老乡  查尔斯·曼森[变态杀人狂]就是你的
Tuco wasn't my homie, anymore than Charlie Manson was yours.
实验室说这是用苯丙酮法制的
Lab says it got cooked, P2P-style.
苯丙酮法
P2P, huh?
你怎么想
So what are you thinking?
是这两个傻贼制的吗
The two stooges over here cooked it?
实验室说这是他们见过的最纯的冰毒
Lab said that blue meth's the purest they've seen.
至少是  自这个之后
At least since this.
-疯狂小八  -疯狂小八  屠库
- Krazy-8  - Krazy-8...Tuco
这些事件都有某种联系
Somehow, some way, it's all connected.
或许有个很简单的解释
A simple explanation...
只是我想不出来  想得我头疼了
Only I'm not seeing it. And it's making my head hurt.
那是因为你研究这破冰毒太上心了
That's 'cause you're working that ugly melon too hard.
闷死了  我们喝啤酒去
It's dead around here. Let's go get a couple of beers.
现在才上午11点
It's 11 in the morning.
我请客
I'm buying.
你请客  见鬼了  难道是过五月节
You're buying? Holy crap. What, is it Cinco de Mayo already?
[五月节:墨西哥重要节日
纪念墨西哥军队战胜法国军队]
惊喜
Surprise!
你个滑头  就是说你
You sneaky bastard, you!
干得漂亮
Very nice work.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
这是什么
What's this?
-看看这个  我喜欢  -枪做得挺像
- Look at that, I love it! - They got the gut right.
谢谢  伙计  谢谢你
Thanks, man. Thank you.
我们给你准备了一个小礼物
We all got you a little something.
我们大家准备的
This is from all of us.
你们不该破费的
You shouldn't have.
你们这帮恶心鬼
You sick, sick puppies.
我爱死它了
I love it!
苹果汁你不喝完吗
You going to finish your apple juice?
不喝了  谢谢  你拿走吧
No thanks, buddy. You take it.
你应该喝了它
You're supposed to drink it.
护士说你得多喝水
The nurse said you have to stay hydrated.
我不渴
But I'm not thirsty.
爸  喝了它
Dad. Drink it.
迟到总比不到好  是吧
Better late than never, huh?
怎么样了  老兄  你还好吗
How you doing, buddy? You all right?
我看到某人来过的标志了哈
I see the Mark of the Beast there, huh?
玛丽早上来过  它们给这地方添了许多生气
Marie stopped by this morning. They really cheer the place up.
我在楼下撞见斯凯勒了
I ran into Sky downstairs.
他们给你准备轮椅呢  你小子占大便宜了
They're rounding up a wheelchair for you, you free-loading bastard!
给我们讲讲枪战的事
So tell us about the shoot-out.
其实  我只是尽职而已
You know... Just doing my job.
前后也就大概5秒钟吧
Whole thing was over in about five seconds.
我说  沃尔特
Say, Walt, you know,
你怎么样
How are you?
我没事
I'm okay.
真的  我感觉很好
Really, I'm feeling fine.
医生把这叫做
The doctor is calling it a...
"孤立发作的暂时性记忆丧失"
An "isolated episode of transient global amnesia."
什么鬼东西
Damn.
就是说非复发性的
Which means non-recurring.
"非复发性"  听起来不错
"Non-recurring." That sounds good.
确实不错
Sounds real good.
我跟你说  你回来真好
I'll tell you what, I'm glad your back.
你可吓死我们了
You really gave us a scare.
听着  汉克
Listen, Hank.
我不知道怎么说好  你出去找我
I don't know what to say. You going out there looking for me
遇到了危险  我很...
Put you in danger, and I'm so...
抱歉  不止是抱歉  完全不止
Sorry, sorry doesn't even cut it. Not nearly.
你担心的就是这个  别傻了
Is that what you're worried about? Forget it. At the office,
同事都拿我当艾略特·奈斯崇拜呢
They're treating me like I'm Elliot Ness, okay?
[艾略特·奈斯  因打击酒类走私著称
可参见著名影片《不可触犯》]
他们给我开派对
They threw me a party,
丫头们给我烤巧克力蛋糕
The gals baked me a chocolate-chip cake
跟你说你都不信
Like you wouldn't believe, okay?
你以后得多失踪几次
You oughtta disappear more often.
开个玩笑  你可千万别
Just kidding. Don't do that.
你看  看他们送给我什么
Hey, look. Look what they gave me.
这是什么
What is it?
这个  是我打死那个人的牙贴
That, gentlemen, is the grill of the guy I shot.
他的牙贴
His grill?
对  他门牙上镶着这个
Yeah, it kind of goes over the front teeth like that, you know?
大概是时髦装饰吧
Sort of a fashion statement, I guess.
有人就是喜欢亮闪闪的东西
Certain folks are attracted to shiny things.
酷啊
Wow, cool.
回家真是无法形容地好
I can't tell you how good it feels to be home.
我把这些拿去洗了
I'll get these in the wash.
亲爱的
Say, honey,
我想去趟7-11便利店
I was just thinking about going out to 7-11.
你要什么吗
Do you need anything?
自由斟[一款饮料  也叫重量杯]
Big Gulp?
牛肉条[一种零食]
Slim Jim?
斯凯勒  听我说
Skyler, listen to me.
这种事不会再发生了  我不会的
This will not happen again, okay? I won't let it.
我还在  很清醒
I'm still here. I'm me.
我们会没事的
And we're gonna be okay.
你是不是有别的手机
Do you have a second cell phone?
别的手机
A second cell phone?
你失踪那天晚上
The night you disappeared,
我泡澡的时候你走进来
You came in when I was taking a bath, and...
看上去很沮丧
You were very upset.
就像是发生了什么可怕的事情
It was like something terrible had happened.
后来你手机响了
And then your cell phone rang.
我见你看了看号码  接了电话  然后
I saw you check the number, and then you got up and...
就那么消失了
Just... disappeared.
可是汉克查你通话记录的时候
And when Hank checked your phone records,
那个时间根本没有通话
There was no call.
我知道的那部手机没有通话记录
No call on the phone I know about.
那可真
That is...
奇怪
Odd.
我完全不记得了
I don't remember any of that.
但我确定一件事
But one thing I am sure of is
我没有别的手机
That I don't have a second cell phone.